OK, so now we're going
to talk about applied hash
functions and particularly
hash functions
applied in blockchains.
So we will
first recap what a hash
function is, and then
we'll start talking a bit
about cryptocurrencies
and what
the main problems are there
that we need to hash
functions to solve.
And then we'll see changing
and blockchains and proof
of work, which are two
solutions to two
problems that we need.
And finally, we'll see
three hashing, which is also
another solution
to another problem that
we will see. So let's
start talking
about hash
function. So what are they?
So am hash functions
or other cryptographic
hash functions are so-called
one way functions.
This means that they have
some desirable property
that you can go one way easily,
but it's very hard to go
the other way. So what does
this mean,
exactly? So. It's commonly
referred to as
three different properties,
so premium
resistance is the first
one. This means that
if we have a hash function
edge and a value
y, then we should
output any X such that
each of X is equal
to Y. And that
is, we are supposed
to find the inverse
order, the pre
image. So why is there
the image? And X
is the pre image that
we are supposed to find.
And if a hash
function is pre image
resistant, then
this is very hard.
And this also
and other another name
for this is one
weightiness. So premature resistance
or hash
function being one way.
And the second
property is second pre-match
resistance, or also known
as weak coalition resistance.
And so in this
problem, we get the hash function
edge, we get the value
x this time. So the pre
image and then
we should find any x
prime such that X of h of X
is equal to each of x
prime. And of course,
x prime should not be
equal. It should be two different
values. So we should
find a coalition. Given a pre
image, we should
find a second pre image
that also
hashes to the same value.
And the last
property is the coalition
resistance or strong
coalition resistance, as
it sometimes
called. And in this case,
we get a hash function edge.
And our job is to find
X and X prime.
Any one of those and we may
choose them as we like.
And the only
requirement is that each of X is equal
to each of them.
They shouldn't be equal,
of course. And so two
different X and X
prime and A to find any
one of these, then
we we say that we find
a coalition. So if edge
his coalition
resistance, then
finding X and X prime is very
hard. So that's
a secure cryptographic
hash function. It has these
properties.
Now, let's proceed
to cryptocurrencies.
So the idea of a bitcoin,
the first
cryptocurrency that while the first
modern
cryptocurrency that we think of there,
there were some other
cryptocurrencies
before which were digital
cash,
but they are not the same
as cryptocurrencies are same
bitcoin and Ethereum
and others.
So the idea
of Nakamoto bitcoin was that
it's supposed to be
decentralized. So we have no
central authority
like a federal bank,
for instance, in in their normal
and monetary
systems. And all
transactions
are in a public log.
And this makes
it sort of democracy
democratized
because it relies on majority
consensus rather
than an authoritative
national bank or a federal
bank or whatever.
And so this was the idea.
And the key is in that
all transactions
are in a public log.
And that's the key idea
of this. And so because this
means that
a transaction
is money. So there
is no money because that's
what digital cash
was or and normal
currency that we use.
And then you actually
have money. But here.
You actually don't
have any money. You just have
transactions and you have
transactions
saying that this public key
has this much value
and then you can transfer
money from one transaction
to another,
essentially. And so if we look at this
figure. We have that. Each
of these are transactions,
and then for a transaction
here you have the owner
of the transaction,
which is the recipient
of not from another
transaction. So we see here
and that this
transaction goes into the next
transaction.
So this one goes
to another owner.
So it's this owner
of a transaction that can
actually use it.
So the way this works
is that this these figures
and transactions
transferring from owner one
to another two and transfer
them to owner three.
And so what happens
is that you have the owners
and public key, which is stored
in the transaction
and then the owner has
their corresponding private key
and you need that
to use a transaction.
And. What do you do is that
you compute a hash
from there when there's
public key. And the previous
transaction
that you are using
and then you actually sign
this. This
needs to be signed
by the previous owner.
So an owner one here wants
to make a transfer to owner
two. What happens is that
we have owner one's
public key that can be used
to verify owner
one's signature here.
So since Owner one
has money, according to this
transaction,
owner one can create
a signature to create
this transaction and put
the owner to public
key. So the recipient has
put that into the hash
and put the actual transaction
into the hash
and then you sign it.
And suddenly,
whatever was in this
transaction now
went over to owner
to because there
is a signature
by owner one so everyone
can verify here that
owner of one here has
signed here, which means now it's
owner two who owns
this and so a transfer
of ownership.
And since there
is such a signature,
there's nothing owner one can do
to retract this.
And then it's it happens
the same. Same when Owner
two wants to transfer
to owner three. That owner
to here creates a new
transaction here
and uses the private key
to sign the hashes from owner
3's public key and this
transaction. So these
are linked and then
it's Owner three
that owns this. And so this
is the idea, the main
idea, we will get more details
later of how these
cryptocurrencies work,
particularly
blockchains are rather
an and decentralised ledger
technologies. Yes, they are more
appropriately called
and. Another one of these
problems that we have
that we must face in this system
is how to try and distribute
transactions in the network
since, well,
there are going
to be a lot of people
interested in these
transactions and what
happens because if they are going
to receive payment,
they need to know if the one
who is actually paying me
has actually made the transaction.
So I actually
have received
the money or not.
And so if we.
Look at this figure,
we have, Bob, here
that has a transaction
that, yeah, maybe
one of those transactions
that we just saw.
And for everyone to know
about these
transactions, Bob has to send them
to everyone else in the network,
as we see here.
And that's pretty
easy, it's just send them.
However, we focus
on security here,
so of course, Bob
can maliciously distribute
transactions. So while
he did transfer
send this transaction to someone,
he creates another
transaction where he tries
to spend the same
money or the same
transaction,
but on something else.
So pay with the same money
twice. And of course,
that shouldn't work
in a functioning
monetary system. So in this
case, he he has a separate
transaction that he sends
to this
person. And then Bob will
attempt to get both
his both these transactions
into the chain
here. That is the idea.
And of course, that
is not acceptable. And.
So that is one problem,
another problem that
we have is. Yeah. Of course,
this can happen and even not
maliciously. And then
the question is, how should
we agree on this
chain because different people
receive and even
if everyone receives all
the transactions, they might
receive them in different
order. And then the question
is what should
the transactions look
like and in what order should
they be and what?
How can we agree on this?
Because everyone
in the system must agree
on exactly how this what this
log looks looks like.
So in this case, we have
some the people
running the it,
just storing the log.
And since this
is a decentralized
system, everyone participating
in the storming
of the log. And this
is the visualization
of the log. So these people
have one block that
they want to submit. One block
each. This guy has
managed to make two blocks that
he wants to get in here.
And this guy has none.
And then we have
these options. So this
is what the chain
looks like. This
is an alternative
to this and this
and this and this.
These two are just
the alternatives to each
other. And but we wanted
to to look like
this. So how do we agree
which which bloc
should be at the head this one,
this one or this one?
And then if we agree on this
one, we should also
replace this one by this one.
So how do we do
this? There that is.
And the other problem that
we are facing. So let's go
to the solutions. So how
we can actually
solve some of these problems.
And so let's get into training
and blockchains.
So as we said, we must
order the transactions
to prevent double
spending and because we don't want
to allow anyone to pay
with the same money twice,
and that's not appreciated.
So how do we solve
this? So the idea
is to create a simple
time stamping
mechanism, and I put
time stamping in quotes
and because it doesn't
really time stamp,
it just creates an ordering.
And so the idea here is that
we take a block
with lots of items in them
and we put them into a hash
and compute the hash.
And we also put in the hash
value of the previous one.
So when we created such a block,
we can create a new
one by adding new items
and then hashing all of these
together, putting
them in a hash and taking,
including the hash of the previous
block. And this
way, we create an ordering
because it's obvious that
these items must
exist after these ones,
since these are included
in the hash here that
is included in this
hash with these.
So we create a sort
of ordering. So this
is an ordering of the set
of transactions, and it's
actually quite similar
to the comet objects in gift.
So same idea
that we have there.
And then the question
is what prevents me
from forging
a bloc and claim
it was before another
block in the timeline?
So. Taking, for instance,
an item from here
claiming it appeared
here. What prevents me
from actually
doing that? So the.
Solution to that
question is that the bloc
that I forge
must have the same hash,
which means if I want
to forge change,
make changes in one
of these blocs. It needs
to arrive at exactly
the same hash as it had
before, which means
the edits I make here
must not change the hash.
This means we must find
a coalition
against this hash
function that we have.
So, or rather,
find the second free
image because we have one
image, we have the hash
value it gets. And now
we need to find a second
image, which gives exactly
the same image,
but with the desired
modifications.
And this was a hard
problem. If the hash
function is a cryptographic
hash function, then
this is difficult to achieve.
Now, let's get into proof
of work, and this
is very interesting
because this will actually
sort of violate
what we just said, and that
was hard. But in a clever
way. And so we'll
see. And so the question
is, why do
we need proof
of work? And that
is because the blockchain
is not fixed and it's
never fixed. It's
continuously extended
and someone can
change the histories
just to just a matter
of making. The others agree
that this one
appeared before. So technically,
we can't rewrite the entire
chain. But we need
to convince
others that this should
happen.
Remember, we had this
picture how
blockchain is agreed
upon. So we need to convince
people that this
is actually what it looks
like and we want
to prevent people from this
one to go back several
blocks to do edits
and submit them and say
that, hey, this is what
the blockchain should look like
and convince the others
to change their view
from this or this
into this one.
Yeah. So how do we do this?
So the idea is that
we want to prevent
and this forgery
because technically these are just
very complete and computed
hash functions.
So if we we can just go back
and this is what
it looks like,
we can just go back and redo
these computations, but with
different
different values and arrive
at a different
head of the chain.
And then
we, yeah, we can
make it the longest chain
and longer than the others
because the consensus
algorithm
in bitcoin, for instance,
that one says that it's
the longest chain
that is the valid one.
So say that. And if this guy
adds one more here, then
it is the then
it should be another
one here too.
And then this one
is obviously the longest,
and this means that
we should dump these two,
which are actually the value
chain and change
to this one.
And so this is easily doable
with just a construction
that we saw
before and because we just
need to re compute
these hashes and we can
do that pretty instantly.
So how do we fix this
problem? How do you make
it hard to change
the history?
Well, we introduced
proof of work.
So the idea
here is that we adapt
the blocks that we saw
before. So we had
the previous hash and we had
the the items before,
but now we add
a nonce value here.
So a number used
ones. So we see here
that the next block
here is based on the previous
block, plus the transactions
and the nonce now, so this
end wasn't here
before on the slide
before and.
And then we also
introduce this
requirement. And this
is what causes
their proof of work.
And because this actually
causes quite
some work. And so what
will happen here
is that. We require
the hash, so the image
to be less
than a particular
value, which means we cannot have
just any hash.
Can't just compute any hash
because that might
not be less than cake.
So what we what we have
to do here is to vary this
nonce and try
to find a nonce
which with this
edge I minus one and this
B.I will yield and be
less than K.
And because this
is this K is the difficulty
that
is adjusted so that if one
of these problems can be
solved and like
every ten minutes.
So if we set this k very
large, then of course
this problem is going
to be much easier.
If we said it very small,
then this problem is going
to be really, really,
really hard. And so we have
to at just this K
and in bitcoin's
case, we adjust it so that one
of these problems can
be solved every ten minutes.
And this is adapted
because they're the size
of the network might
change and there'd be be different.
So a different different
amount of notes participate
in in the network
and to solve this.
These
problems. So the the idea
here is that we have
the proof of work
problem. Which is this?
And then we have Kay,
which is a value so and a little
bit. We assume
it's a little bit long.
It's less than two to the power
of L. And so that
makes it this long.
And then
if the the image
so the hash value
y has to be
less than K, that means
that this part is actually
fixed to zeros.
And so then we have
a fixed pretty image,
which means we don't have
such a difficult
problem, after all. It's not like
finding a pre
image, but rather somewhat
like that because we are still
allowed to vary
here. And so if you compare
this
to the pre-match problem,
then the entire
thing is fixed. So we have
to find this. Exact one.
There is only one
that we have to to to find
asks, which is one
out of two to the power
of 256 possible ones.
But if we look at the problem,
the proof of work
problem, we see that
it's only this that is fixed.
So there are these
many bits that we can actually
vary that
are allowed to vary
for days to solve.
So it's much easier
pre-match problem
than the actual and pretty
much problem. And by.
Varying Kay,
here we we vary the bits
that are here, which means
we can control how difficult
it is safer shrink,
and that means it shrinks
in this direction.
That means the fixed pre image
is increasing.
So if we set K to like
one or zero, then
it's all the way down
here. So then we have the full
scale and cryptographic
pre-match problem.
Yeah, so we can control
how difficult the pre-match
problem is supposed to be.
Now, let's go
to three hashing.
And remember
that we have this time
stamping mechanism,
and this is to prevent
forgery, which means
that we need to.
Verify
whenever there is a new
transaction that uses an all
transaction, we must go
back. And find
that all transaction
in some block and then
check that it has not been used
in any other
block since then.
And so this is computing
a lot of hashes
and we would like
this to be efficient.
That's why we use a so-called
Merkle tree.
So the idea here
is we want to include
and we want to include
these data blocks. So L1, L2,
L3, L4. And create
a hash for them
and then be able to check
if one was present.
So the way
we do this is that
we hash each of them.
This creates a hash value.
Then we hash
these hash values
so we create a tree
structure and then we hash
this so we get
to the top hash.
And we can do
this for transactions
at. In this way,
because the advantage
here now, if you want
to verify that this
transaction three actually
is in this block,
then we take this compute
the hash of it.
Then we get hash three,
which we don't need
to have because we can
compute it. We need
hash to, but we don't need
to have the transaction
that comes that generated this
hash. And because that
one might be much bigger
than the hash value. So this
is saving us from space
because their hash
value might be 256 bit or,
say, 512 instead
of several megabytes
that the actual
transaction might be.
So then we we have saved
a lot of space by just having
the hash value here
instead. We can hash this one. So now
we have the two hash
values, we can compute this one.
And but we also need
the other leg of this tree.
So we need this hash
instead of all the transactions
and hash just that
it represents. We can
hash these together. We get
the root and we see that
everything competes.
So this means that we need
to store much less data that
to do the verification
than we would have
needed otherwise.
So this helps us make
things a bit more
efficient. And that was everything that
I wanted to say
about applied hash functions
and blockchains.